J. Robert Oppenheimer Papers
Manuscript Division, Library of Congress
- General Case File, 1799-1967 (Box 14-79)
  - Tomei, Anthony A. (Box 73)
    - Correspondence
      - Oppenheimer, J. Robert, 1947-1952
      - Russell, Katherine, 1947-1952
    - Itineraries, 1950
    - Top secret inventories, 1949-1952
  - Tomonaga, Sin-itiro, 1948-1965
  - Tonks, Lewi, 1955-1963
  - Toward Liberal Education, 1965-1967
  - Truman, Harry S.
    - Correspondence
      - To Oppenheimer, 1946-1952
      - From Oppenheimer, 1946-1952
    - Hydrogen bomb statement, undated
  - Turin University, Turin, Italy, 1952
  - Turkevich, John, 1952-1955
  - Tuve, Merle, 1947-1952
  - “U” miscellaneous, 1943-1966
  - Uehling, Edwin A., 1949-1965
  - Ultrahigh Energy Accelerator Conference, 1960 (Box 74)
  - UNESCO Round Table, New Delhi, India, 1966
  - Urey, Harold C., 1950-1965
  - “V” miscellaneous, 1943-1968, (2 folders)
  - Vaidya, P. C., 1950-1951
  - Valentine, Alan C., 1949-1950
  - Vallarta, Manuel Sandoval, 1947-1962
  - Valley Forge Foundation, 1951-1952
  - Van den Bergh, Louis, 1948-1950
  - Van Hove, Léon, 1954-1958
  - Van Vleck, J. H., 1942-1951
  - Vesugar, Jamshed, 1950
  - Veterans Administration, 1948-1951
  - Vincent, John H., 1957
  - Vinot, P., 1954-1956
  - Visa problems, 1952-1957
  - Vishinsky, Andrey Yanuaryevich, 1949
  - Voice of America, 1949 (Box 75)
  - Volpe, Joseph, 1947-1963
  - Voluntary Organizations and a World Without War Conference, 1963
  - Von Neumann, John, 1948-1952
  - “Wa-Wi” miscellaneous, 1945-1967, (5 folders)
  - "Wo-Wy" miscellaneous, 1946-1966, (2 folders) (Box 76)
  - W. A. Benjamin, Inc. See Container 19, Benjamin (W. A.), Inc.
  - Waksman, Selman A., 1949-1963
  - War crimes trials, 1948
  - Ward, John, 1954-1955
  - Warner, Edith, 1945-1958
  - Warren, Shields, 1949-1952
  - Watanabe, Michael S. See also Container 30, Dauer, Dorothea W.
    - Correspondence, 1945-1953
    - Publications, 1941-1947
  - Waterman, Alan T., 1948-1963
  - Waymack, William W.
    - Correspondence, 1948-1949
    - Remarks as commissioner, 1947-1948
  - Weaver, Warren, 1946-1963 (Box 77)
  - Webster, William, 1949-1951
  - Weil, George L.
    - Correspondence, 1948-1952 See also Classified
    - Publications and talks, 1948-1952
  - Weinbaum, Sidney, 1950-1966
  - Weinberg, Alvin M., 1946-1951
  - Weinberg, Joseph W.
    - General reference, 1943-1962
    - Perjury trial, 1953 See also Container 237, same heading
  - Weisskopf, Victor F. (“Viki”), 1942-1965
  - Weizmann, Chaim, 1947-1965
  - Weizmann Memorial, 1953
  - Weizsäcker, C. R. von, 1950
  - Western Accelerator Group, 1961
  - Western Printing and Lithographing Co., 1959-1961
  - Wheeler, John, 1942-1966 (Box 78)
  - White, Morton, 1954-1963
  - White, Stephen, 1947-1963
  - White, Theodore H. (1915-1986), 1956-1966
  - White House dinner, 1962
  - Whitman, Walter G., 1950-1953
  - Whitney (John Hay) Foundation, 1950
  - Wick, Gian Carlo, 1947-1967
  - Wigner, Eugene P., 1946-1963
  - Williams, John H., 1942-1966
  - Williams, Walter J., 1948-1950
  - Wilson, Carroll L., 1947-1952
  - Wilson, H. A., 1942-1953
  - Wilson, Robert E., 1948
  - Wilson, Robert R., 1950-1964
  - Winne, Harry A., 1946-1949
  - Wofford, Harris, 1951-1952
  - Wolff, Harold Arnold, 1948
  - Wolman, Abel, 1948-1951
  - Woodward, Ernest Llewelyn, 1953-1963
  - World Book Encyclopedia, 1952-1953
  - World Council of Peace, 1952-1956
  - World Union, 1945-1946
  - World Without War Conference See Container 152, Voluntary Organizations and a World Without War Conference Worthington, Hood
  - Wouthuysen, S., 1949-1958 (Box 79)
  - Wrinch, Dorothy, 1941-1949
  - Wyman, Jeffries, 1956-1958
  - Wyzanski, Charles E., 1952-1964
  - "Y" miscellaneous, 1942-1966
  - Yang, Chen Ning, 1949-1966
  - Yevick, Miriam, 1952-1961
  - Yost, Don M., 1943
  - Yourgrau, Wolfgang, 1956-1965
  - Yukawa, Hideki, 1948-1965
  - “Z” miscellaneous, 1946-1965
  - Zacharias, Jerrold, 1954-1963
  - Zeitlin and Ver Brugge Booksellers, 1950-1952
  - Zinn, W. H., 1947-1949
  - Unidentified, 1941-1966
- Invitation Correspondence, 1946-1967 (Box 80-109)
  Letters received and copies of letters sent, memoranda, secretary's notes, clippings, and printed matter.
  Arranged alphabetically by name of organization or person.
  - “A" miscellaneous (Box 80)
    - Aa-Al, 1945-1967, (2 folders)
    - American A-W, 1945-1967, (4 folders)
    - An-Av, 1946-1967, (3 folders) (Box 81)
  - Air University, Maxwell Air Force Base, Alabama, 1948-1953
  - Alabama, 1949-1959
  - Allen, George E., 1951-1953
  - American Academy of Arts and Letters, 1951-1964
  - American Academy of Arts and Sciences, 1956-1963
  - American Academy of Political and Social Science, 1948-1954
  - American Association for the Advancement of Science, 1949-1965
  - American Broadcasting Co., 1949-1965
  - American Chemical Society, 1947-1964
  - American Civil Liberties Union, 1955-1964 (Box 82)
  - American Committee on United Europe, 1950-1952
  - American Council for Judaism, 1955-1965
  - American Council of Learned Societies, 1951-1957
  - American Council on NATO See Container 98, NATO, American Council on
  - American Friends Service Committee, 1956-1963
  - American Institute of Electrical Engineers, 1950-1959
  - American Institute of Physics, 1948-1967
  - American Jewish Congress, 1956-1959
  - American Nobel Memorial Foundation, 1961-1964
  - American Philosophical Society, 1948-1957
  - American Society of Group Psychotherapy and Psychodrama, 1957
  - American Unitarian Association, 1950-1960
  - American Veterans Committee, 1948-1957
  - Americans for Democratic Action, 1955-1964
  - Amherst College, Amherst, Mass., 1948-1964
  - Anshe Emet Synagogue, Chicago, Ill., 1955-1956
  - Anti-Defamation League of B'nai B'rith, 1949-1959
  - Antioch College, Yellow Springs, Ohio, 1951-1963
  - Appleton-Century-Crofts, 1958-1966
  - Aspen Institute for Humanistic Studies, 1949-1965 (Box 83)
  - Associated Press, 1957-1964
  - “B” miscellaneous, 1945-1967, (4 folders)
  - Baltimore Sun, 1956-1966
  - Bard College, Annandale-On-Hudson, N.Y., 1953-1965
  - Barnett R. Brickner Memorial Foundation See Container 84, Brickner (Barnett R.) Memorial Foundation
  - Basic Books, Inc., 1954-1966
  - Bennington College, Bennington, Vt., 1956-1956
  - B'nai B'rith, 1954-1966
  - Bowdoin College, Brunswick, Maine, 1950-1962
  - Brandeis University, Waltham, Mass., 1953-1965 (Box 84)
  - Brickner (Barnett R.) Memorial Foundation, 1959-1963
  - British Association for the Advancement of Science, 1947-1955
  - Brooklyn College, Brooklyn, N.Y., 1955-1964
  - Brown University, Providence, R.I., 1950-1964
  - Bryn Mawr College, Bryn Mawr, Pa., 1948-1964
  - Bucknell University, Lewisburg, Pa., 1957-1961
  - Buffalo, University of, Buffalo, N.Y., 1947-1962
  - Bulletin of the Atomic Scientists, 1955-1962
  - “C” miscellaneous
    - Ca-Col, 1946-1967, (6 folders)
    - Com-Cu, 1946-1966, (3 folders) (Box 85)
  - California Institute of Technology, Pasadena, Calif., 1948, 1962
  - California, University of, Berkeley, Calif., 1949-1966
  - Canadian Broadcasting Corp., 1953-1967 (Box 86)
  - Canadian Institute of Public Affairs, 1955-1963
  - Canadian National Research Council, 1954-1955
  - Case Institute of Technology, Cleveland, Ohio, 1948-1966
  - Chalk River, Ontario, Canada, National Research Council, 1949
  - Chemical Institute of Canada, 1950-1963
  - Chicago, University of, Chicago, Ill., 1948-1966
  - Christ's College, University of Cambridge, Cambridge, England, 1955-1960
  - Church Peace Mission, 1957-1959
  - Church Peace Union, 1950-1958
  - City College of New York, New York, N.Y., 1950-1966
  - City of Hope, Los Angeles, Calif., 1958-1964
  - Coe College, Cedar Rapids, Iowa, 1951-1959
  - Colby College, Waterville, Maine, 1952-1966
  - Colgate University, Hamilton, N.Y., 1950-1956
  - Colorado, University of, Boulder, Colo., 1955-1965
  - Columbia Broadcasting System, 1948-1965 (Box 87)
  - Columbia University, New York, N.Y., 1947-1966
  - Concordia College, Moorhead, Minn., 1955-1957
  - Conference on Science, Philosophy and Religion, 1950-1955
  - Connecticut, University of, Storrs, Conn., 1951-1955
  - Cooper Union, New York, N.Y., 1953-1965
  - Cooperative Forum, 1949-1958
  - Cornell University, Ithaca, N.Y., 1953-1963
  - Corning Glass Works Conference, Corning, N.Y., 1951
  - Czechoslovak news services, 1957-1963
  - “D” miscellaneous, 1945-1967, (2 folders)
  - Dartmouth College, Hanover, N.H., 1949-1962 (Box 88)
  - Dartmouth College Phi Beta Kappa, 1953
  - D-Club, Princeton, N.J., undated
  - Delaware, University of, Newark, Del., 1961-1962
  - Dillard University, New Orleans, La., 1952-1953
  - Dinner Club, 1955-1958
  - Dokumente, 1955
  - Dropsie College, Philadelphia, Pa., 1957-1959
  - Duke University, Durham, N.C., 1948-1965
  - “E” miscellaneous, 1946-1967, (3 folders)
  - Echo Lake, Colo., conferences, 1948-1955 (Box 89)
  - Encampment for Citizenship, 1954-1959
  - Encounter, 1957-1965
  - Eranos conferences, 1950-1958
  - Esquire, 1954-1966
  - “F” miscellaneous, 1946-1966, (2 folders)
  - Federation of American Scientists, 1950-1965
  - Fieldston School, New York, N.Y., 1948-1966
  - First Unitarian Church, San Francisco, Calif., 1961-1966
  - Ford Hall Forum, 1955-1962
  - Foreign Affairs, 1951-1967
  - Foreign Policy Association, 1946-1958
  - Foundation for Integrated Education, 1948-1958
  - Franklin and Marshall College, Lancaster, Pa., 1952-1964
  - Franklin Institute, Philadelphia, Pa., 1950-1966
  - Freedom Forum, 1947-1956 (Box 90)
  - Freedom House, 1951-1953
  - Freedom petition, Hungarian, 1957
  - French Broadcasting System, 1949-1959
  - Fund for Adult Education, 1957-1959
  - “G” miscellaneous, 1946-1967, (2 folders)
  - Gary Teachers Union, Gary, Ind., 1948-1958
  - General Electric Co., 1946-1959
  - Goddard College, Plainfield, Vt., 1950-1963
  - Golden anniversary of the City of New York, N.Y., 1948
  - Goucher College, Towson, Md., 1953
  - Great Books of the Western World, 1952
  - “H” miscellaneous
    - Ha-He, 1949-1966
    - Hi-Hy, 1946-1967 (Box 91)
  - Hamilton College, Clinton, N.Y., 1951-1958
  - Harcourt, Brace and Co., 1947-1959
  - Harper and Row, 1946-1966
  - Harvard Club, 1949-1967
  - Harvard Law School, Cambridge, Mass., 1955-1965
  - Harvard Law School Forum, Cambridge, Mass., 1950-1960
  - Harvard University, Cambridge, Mass., 1947-1967, (2 folders)
  - Haverford College, Haverford, Pa., 1954-1965
  - Henry Schuman, Inc. See Container 104, Schuman (Henry) Inc.
  - Horizon, 1948-1958
  - Houghton Mifflin Co., 1950-1953
  - “I” miscellaneous, 1946-1967, (2 folders) (Box 92)
  - Illinois State Normal University, Normal, Ill., 1952-1959
  - Illinois, University of, Urbana, Ill., 1949-1957
  - India, government of, 1951-1961
  - Indian Science Congress Association, 1955
  - Industrial Research Institute, 1949-1951
  - Institute of Contemporary Arts, 1955-1958
  - Institute of Radio Engineers, 1948-1958
  - International Business Machines Corp., 1948-1959
  - International Commission for Applied Ecology, 1957-1958
  - International Conference on Elementary Particle Physics, Pisa, Italy, 1955
  - International House, New York, N.Y., 1955-1961
  - International News Service, 1949-1957
  - International Rescue Committee, 1951-1954
  - International Union of Physics, 1949
  - Iowa State College, Cedar Falls, Iowa, 1948-1964
  - Iowa State University, Ames, Iowa, 1950-1964
  - “J” miscellaneous, 1946-1966 (Box 93)
  - Japan International Conference on Theoretical Physics, 1951-1953
  - Jeunet, André, 1957-1958
  - Jewish Agency for Palestine, 1955
  - Jewish centers, 1949-1965
  - Jewish miscellany, 1948-1966
  - Jewish Theological Seminary of America, New York, N.Y., 1950-1967
  - Johns Hopkins University, Baltimore, Md., 1951-1962
  - Junior Chamber of Commerce, 1950
  - “K” miscellaneous, 1948-1966
  - Kent State University, Kent, Ohio, 1949-1964 (Box 94)
  - Kenyon College, Gambier, Ohio, 1946-1960
  - “L” miscellaneous, 1945-1967, (5 folders)
  - Lehigh Valley Newspaper Guild, 1950-1952
  - Little, Brown and Co., 1949-1966
  - Little Red School House, New York, N.Y., 1956-1959
  - Longmans, Green and Co., 1955
  - “M” miscellaneous
    - Ma-Me, 1946-1966
    - Mi-My, 1946-1967, (2 folders) (Box 95)
  - Macalester College, St. Paul, Minn., 1949-1960
  - MacLeish, Archibald, 1948
  - Macmillan Co., 1952-1965
  - Maecon, 1959
  - Manitoba, University of, Winnipeg, Canada, 1959
  - Mankind, 1957
  - Maryland, University of, College Park, Md., 1950-1964
  - Massachusetts, University of, Amherst, Mass., 1958-1965
  - Massachusetts Institute of Technology, Cambridge, Mass., 1950-1966
  - McGill University, Montreal, Canada, 1955-1963
  - McGraw-Hill Book Co., 1947-1965
  - “Meet the Press”, 1945-1957 (Box 96)
  - Michigan, University of, Ann Arbor, Mich., 1949-1960
  - Middlebury College, Middlebury, Vt., 1948-1963
  - Mills College, Oakland, Calif., 1950-1961
  - Minnesota, University of, Minneapolis, Minn., 1951-1966
  - Miss Fine's School, Princeton, N.J., 1949-1965
  - Missouri, University of, Columbia, Mo., 1951-1965
  - Modern Forum, 1952-1964
  - Mount Allison University, Sackville, Canada, 1958
  - Mount Holyoke College, South Hadley, Mass., 1948-1966
  - Mount Sinai Hospital, New York, N.Y., 1952-1955
  - Museum of Modern Art, New York, N.Y., 1952-1959
  - “N” miscellaneous
    - Na, 1946-1967, (3 folders)
    - Ne-Nu, 1946-1967, (2 folders) (Box 97)
  - Nassau Club, 1947-1963
  - Natal, University of, Durban, South Africa, 1959-1960
  - Nation Associates, 1946-1964
  - National Association of Women Deans and Counselors, 1957
  - National Book Awards, 1958-1967
  - National Broadcasting Co., 1952-1965
  - National Conference of Christians and Jews, 1947-1952
  - National Council of Jewish Women, 1948-1966
  - National Industrial Conference Board, 1953-1955 (Box 98)
  - National Press Club, 1955
  - National Science Teachers Association, 1951-1965
  - National Society for the Study of Communication, 1953-1955
  - National Student Council of the Young Men's Christian Association, 1949-1956
  - NATO, American Council on, 1953
  - Nebraska, University of, Lincoln, Nebr., 1947-1955
  - New Jersey Academy of Science, 1956-1964
  - New Jersey College for Women, New Brunswick, N.J., 1947-1950
  - New Jersey State Teachers College, Montclair, N.J., 1955-1964
  - New Leader, 1955-1962
  - New Republic, 1947-1964
  - New School for Social Research, New York, N.Y., 1946-1966
  - New York Academy of Medicine, 1948-1960
  - New York Academy of Sciences, 1948-1961
  - New York Bar Association, 1964
  - New York Herald Tribune, 1947-1963
  - New York, State University of, various campuses, 1948-1966 (Box 99)
  - New York Times, 1946-1965
  - New York University, New York, N.Y., 1948-1967
  - New York World Telegram, 1957-1959
  - Newsday, 1957-1965
  - Newsweek, 1950-1962
  - North Carolina, University of, Chapel Hill, N.C., 1946-1966
  - North Carolina State College, Raleigh, N.C., 1952-1962
  - North Shore Forum, Congregation Israel, Glencoe, Ill., 1956-1958
  - Northwestern University, Evanston, Ill., 1951-1964
  - Notre Dame, University of, Notre Dame, Ind., 1953-1965
  - Nucleonics, 1951-1955
  - “O” miscellaneous, 1946-1967
  - Oberlin College, Oberlin, Ohio, 1955-1966
  - Ohio State University, Columbus, Ohio, 1948-1966
  - On Film, Inc., 1961
  - Oxford University Press, 1952-1958
  - “P” miscellaneous, 1946-1967, (4 folders) (Box 100)
  - Pageant, 1950-1966
  - Partisan Review, 1952-1966
  - Pennsylvania Bar Association, 1951-1957
  - Pennsylvania, University of, Philadelphia, Pa., 1947-1966
  - Pennsylvania State University, University Park, Pa., 1947-1962
  - Pergamon Press, 1957-1963
  - Phi Beta Kappa, 1949-1964 (Box 101)
  - Philadelphia Ethical Society, Philadelphia, Pa., 1953-1955
  - Philosophical Library, New York, N.Y., 1947-1953
  - Polytechnic Institute of Brooklyn, Brooklyn, N.Y., 1950-1959
  - Portland City Club, Portland, Oreg., 1954-1959
  - Princeton, N.J., 1948-1963
  - Princeton Theological Seminary, Princeton, N.J., 1954-1957
  - Princeton University, Princeton, N.J., 1946-1966, (2 folders)
  - Prix Nessim Habif, 1965-1966
  - Product Engineering, 1958-1959
  - Prospetti, 1954-1955
  - Pugwash, 1960-1962
  - Purdue University, West Lafayette, Ind., 1946-1963
  - “Q” miscellaneous, 1949-1965
  - “R” miscellaneous
    - Ra-Ri, 1946-1966, (2 folders)
    - Ro-Ru, 1946-1967 (Box 102)
  - Radio Corporation of America, 1951
  - Radio stations
    - KMLA, Los Angeles, Calif., 1958
    - KPFA, Berkeley, Calif., 1953-1955
  - Reed College, Portland, Oreg., 1946-1961
  - Rensselaer Polytechnic Institute, Troy, N.Y., 1949-1966
  - Reporter, 1953-1960
  - Rhein-Ruhr-Klub, 1955-1958
  - Rhode Island, University of, Kingston, R.I., 1953-1963
  - Rinehart and Co., 1953-1955
  - Rochester, University of, Rochester, N.Y., 1949-1965
  - Roosevelt College, Chicago, Ill., 1950-1955
  - Rutgers University, New Brunswick, N.J., 1948-1966
  - “S” miscellaneous
    - Sa-Sm, 1945-1966, (3 folders)
    - So-Sz, 1945-1966, (5 folders) (Box 103)
  - St. John's College, Annapolis, Md., 1948-1959
  - St. Mark's School, Southborough, Mass., 1966
  - San Diego State College, San Diego, Calif., 1958-1965
  - San Francisco Press Club, San Francisco, Calif., 1948-1949
  - Sarah Lawrence College, Bronxville, N.Y., 1952-1962 (Box 104)
  - Saturday Review, 1947-1966
  - School for Nursery Years, Los Angeles, Calif., 1958-1959
  - Schuman (Henry) Inc., 1947-1949
  - Science, 1947-1965
  - Science, Philosophy and Religion Conference, 1958-1959
  - Science Service, 1948-1954
  - Science Talent Search, 1951-1952
  - Scientia, 1951
  - Sigma Pi Sigma, 1948
  - Sir George Williams College, Montreal, Canada, 1958-1959
  - Sloan Foundation. See Container 287, Weaver's Symposium
  - Sloan-Kettering Institute, 1948-1955
  - Smith College, Northampton, Mass., 1947-1966
  - Société Européenne de Culture, 1957-1963
  - Society for Advancement of Management, 1949-1952
  - Society for Ethical Culture, 1950-1955
  - Southern California, University of, Los Angeles, Calif., 1949-1964
  - Stanford University, Stanford, Calif., 1951-1967
  - State Department, 1951-1966 (Box 105)
  - Stephens College, Columbia, Mo., 1948-1958
  - Stockbridge School, Interlaken, Mass., 1955-1958
  - Swarthmore College, Swarthmore, Pa., 1949-1958
  - Syracuse University, Syracuse, N.Y., 1948-1965
  - “T” miscellaneous, 1946-1966, (3 folders)
  - Tamiment Institute and Library, New York, N.Y., 1956-1958
  - Tata Institute of Fundamental Research, Bombay, India, 1961-1963
  - Teachers Union, 1950-1954
  - Technion, 1952-1963
  - Temples, various, 1949-1966
  - Texaco Research Club, 1951-1953
  - Texas, University of, Austin, Tex., 1947-1964
  - This Week Magazine, 1958-1962 (Box 106)
  - Time, 1946-1966
  - Toronto, University of, Toronto, Canada, 1955-1964
  - “U” miscellaneous, 1946-1967, (2 folders)
  - UNESCO, 1966
  - Unions, various, 1950-1964
  - Unitarian Universalist Association, 1954-1966
  - United Church, 1948-1950
  - United Jewish Appeal, 1948-1959
  - United Press International, 1947-1963
  - United States, miscellaneous, 19461966
  - United States Junior Chamber of Commerce, 1948-1953
  - United States Lines, 1958 (Box 107)
  - United States National Student Association, 1954-1958
  - United World Federalists, 1947-1964
  - University Club of Philadelphia, Philadelphia, Pa., 1949-1952
  - “V” miscellaneous, 1946-1966
  - Valley Green, Passaic Valley High School, Little Falls, N.J., 1957-1958
  - Vanderbilt University, Nashville, Tenn., 1949-1965
  - Van Nostrand Co., 1950-1963
  - Vassar College, Poughkeepsie, N.Y., 1948-1962
  - Veterans Administration Hospital, Topeka, Kans., 1954-1956
  - Virginia Quarterly Review, 1953-1959
  - Virginia, University of, Charlottesville, Va., 1950-1962
  - “W” miscellaneous
    - Wa-Wo, 1946-1966, (3 folders)
    - Wo-Wy, 1947-1964 (Box 108)
  - Wallace, Mike, 1957-1958
  - Wayne State University, Detroit, Mich., 1950-1966
  - Washington Post, 1947-1966
  - Washington University, St. Louis, Mo., 1952-1964
  - Washington, University of, Seattle, Wash., 1953-1965
  - Wedge Award luncheons, 1948-1949
  - Weizmann Institute of Science, Rehovoth, Israel, 1955-1962
  - Wellesley College, Wellesley, Mass., 1948-1966
  - Wesleyan University, Middletown, Conn., 1948-1962
  - Western Printing and Lithographing Co., 1958
  - Western Reserve University, Cleveland, Ohio, 1950-1964
  - Westinghouse Broadcasting Co. and Westinghouse Electric Corp., 1955-1967
  - Westminster Choir College, Princeton, N.J., and Westminster Recording Co., 1956-1958
  - Wichita, Kans., re University of Wichita, Wichita Eagle, and Wichita State University, 1950-1966
  - Williams College, Williamstown, Mass., 1950-1961
  - Wisconsin, University of, various campuses, 1952-1966 (Box 109)
  - WNEW television station, 1957-1959
  - Women's International League for Peace and Freedom, 1955-1963
  - Woodrow Wilson Foundation, 1952-1958
  - Wooster College, Wooster, Ohio, 1948-1962
  - World Book Encyclopedia, 1951-1966
  - World Brotherhood, Inc., 1956-1960
  - World Peace Conference, Japan, 1964
  - World, miscellaneous, 1948-1965
  - “X-Y-Z” miscellaneous, 1949-1966
  - Yale University, New Haven, Conn., 1947-1966
  - Young Men's and Young Women's Hebrew Association, 1950-1964
  - Young Men's Christian Association and Young Women's Christian Association, 1948-1961
- Membership File, 1943-1967 (Box 110-153)
  Letters received and copies of letters sent, memoranda, secretary's notes, clippings, minutes, and printed material.
  Arranged alphabetically by name of organization.
  - “A” miscellaneous, 1946-1962 (Box 110)
  - Academy of American Poets, 1963-1964
  - Aid Refugee Chinese Intellectuals, Inc., 1952
  - Aldous Huxley Memorial Lectureship, 1964-1966
  - American Academic Freedom Project
    - Arden House conference, 1952-1953
    - Correspondence, 1952
    - Meetings, 1951-1953
    - Memorandum, 1952-1954
    - Oppenheimer appointments, 1951
  - American Academy of Arts and Sciences
    - Correspondence, 1944-1964
    - Daedalus, 1963-1966
    - Fellowship nominations, 1948-1965
    - Membership appraisals, 1955-1956
  - American Civil Liberties Union
    - Correspondence, 1953-1966
    - Hydrogen bomb, censorship, 1950
    - Lasker Award, 1959-1963
    - National committee, 1949-1965
  - American Committee for Cultural Freedom, 1952-1957
  - American Committee for Observance of Tenth Anniversary of Israel, 1957-1958 (Box 111)
  - American Committee on United Europe, 1950
  - American Council of Learned Societies
    - Appointment of Oppenheimer, 1957-1960
    - Committee on Humanities
      - Correspondence with Howard M. Jones, 1955-1959
      - Meeting arrangements, 1955-1957
      - Miscellaneous, 1956-1959
      - Oppenheimer appointment, 1955
      - Reports of meetings, 1955-1960, (2 folders)
      - Summary of activities, 1955
      - Worcester Conference, Worcester, Mass., 1957 1955-1956
  - American Council on Education, 1949-1955
  - American Friends of the Hebrew University See Container 129, Hebrew University, American Friends of the
  - American Institute of Physics (Box 112)
    - Ballots, 1925-1957
    - Governing Board
      - Memoranda, 1949-1956
      - Meetings
        - Arrangements, 1949-1960
        - Minutes, 1949-1951
      - Oppenheimer appointment, 1948-1949
    - Miscellaneous correspondence, 1943-1956
    - Reports, 1949-1952
  - American Inventors Society, 1951
  - American Jewish Committee, 1947-1949
  - American Philosophical Society
    - Election of members, 1949-1962
    - International Relations Program Committee, 1947
    - Meetings, arrangements, 1947-1963
    - Memoranda, 1947-1962 (Box 113)
    - Miscellaneous correspondence, 1945-1962
  - American Physical Society
    - AAAS Centennial Policy Committee, 1948